L96.netlify.com

Laurie Copley Curriculum Vitae



October 2019 lauriemail@protonmail.com

frontend web developer mobile web specialist expertese in accessibility

skills

I have an advanced understanding of:

- HTML, CSS(3) and SASS.
- JavaScript (ES6), jQuery, AngularJs
- React, Redux and React Native
- Gulp, Git, Velocity or Freemarker templates
- Agile(SCRUM)

I have intermediate understanding of: Gradle, Web components, Flutter, Vue.js, Vuex, SQL, Maven, Webpack

I am currently studying: Dutch Language, GraphQL, Native app development

qualifications

Google Mobile Web Specialist

January 2019

This examination tested my knowledge on the following topics:

Website Layout and Styling, Front End Networking, Accessibility, Progressive Web Apps, Performance Optimization and Caching, Testing and Debugging, Mobile Web Forms

A-Levels & VWOs

I studied 1 A-Level at Bourne Grammar School, UK. The school recognised my profeciency at programming and allowed me to complete A-Level Computing a year early. I completed this course with grade A.

After moving to Netherlands I completed 2 VWOs: Physics & Maths.

work experience

Rezzonation

July 2019 - Present

Rezzonation is a small startup which aims to provide a cross-platform media streaming application. Their USP is their ability to link all media streaming services under one application (radio, spotify, youtube etc).

Rezzonation taught me entrepreneurial skills and how to work on a prototype, rather than a product in production. Our technology stack included:

React Native, Redux, React Sagas,

Webpack, Node.is

ISAAC

April 2017 - March 2019

ISAAC is rated the best full-service internet agency by an independant auditor, Emerce 100. I was hired with no diploma, as a motivated trainee. After 6 months of training, I was promoted directly to Software Developer. For the duration of my stay at ISAAC I was assigned to the client Ingenico. A team of 20 collegues and I worked in the SCRUM methodology to produce and maintain a complex payment platform that is capable of serving millions of transactions per day. Our technology stack included: AngularJS (although we were migrating to React.is and typescript), SASS, Gulp, Velocity and freemarker, Java, maven, springboot

DHL Intergamma

August 2016 - March 2017

Whilst I was self-studying web technology and JavaScript, I was a Hefttrukchaffeur. Once I was confident with my skills at JavaScript, I applied at ISAAC.







electronic music producer foundation chairman english accent

background

I'm a 23 year old British guy called Laurie. I fell in love with the Netherlands from visiting electronic music events as a teenager. At the age of 18, I followed my dreams and moved here. It is my goal to eventually naturalise and swap my British passport for a Dutch one. I admire the Dutch way of life, and consider myself more European than British.

Software development has always been a part of my life. At age 13 I became enticed with programming languages from hosting my own Runescape private server. I started web developing as a favour for family friends who wanted inexpensive websites. It wasn't long before I realised these were profitable skills, so I started freelancing for other clients.







the orchestra

The Orchestra is a non-profit audiovisual collective in Eindhoven. I started the Orchestra with 8 likeminded, international friends in Eindhoven. Within the foundation, I am the 'Chairman' and 'Communications Manager'.

We've built and manage a music studio in the city centre which acts a rehearsal and recording space for amateur electronic musicians.

We also host two different event concepts: *The Opera* and *Operetta*. Our events act as a showcase for musicians who rehearse and produce in our workshop, as well as other amateur musicians in the area.

With both of these initiatives combined, we are an effective music launch platform with the sole purpose of supporting local talent.

As well as providing a platform for amateur musicians, some of the proceeds from our events go towards developing custom laser stage effect systems which are put to use in our events. We custom design PCBs, solder all the components and write our own code to make this happen.



So far we have 22 youth members of the Music Studio, had 3 successful events, and have obtained funding from Eindhoven City to host an audiovisual experience on 26th October for Dutch Design Week.

hobbies

Music is very important to me. I attend a music event most weekends and aim for variation. This has inspired me to produce music myself with drum machines and synthesisers. At ISAAC, I set up a "ISAAC Electronic Music Makers" club, which would meet monthly for jam sessions and to exchange tips and tricks.

I am an avid collector of vinyl records, and very old, primitive Russian cameras in lomography style. Using these cameras has taught me patience, camera theory, DIY developing and a steady hand! On this page are some photos I have taken with my USSR cameras.



Developer, ISAAC

Client at ISAAC, Ingenico.